PETER ABOLUDE

CONTACT

Phone +2348132382673

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/abolude-peter

Email

aboludepeter@

gmail.com

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Crawford University,

Lusada

B.Sc. Computer Science

September 2012 - July 2016

GPA: 3.0.

Project: Design and implement an E-senate Application. (Real-Time Chat App for

lecturers).

PROFILE

Peter Abolude brings over 3 years of experience in Cloud Engineering and Software Development. He has successfully delivered projects utilizing various Cloud tools including Infrastructure-as-Code (ARM, BICEP), Automation, Monitoring, and CI/CD tools. At present, Peter holds the position of Technical Lead at Tek Experts,

overseeing a team of 10+ engineers providing support to Azure

Platform-as-a-Service users. This role has allowed him to gain extensive expertise in utilizing Azure services such as App Service, Azure DevOps, Azure Storage, and

Azure Static Web Apps.

SKILLS / ACHIEVEMENTS

Cloud Technologies: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services.

Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployments (CI/CD): CircleCI, Jenkins, Azure DevOps (Azure Pipelines).

Infrastructure As Code (IAC): Azure Resource Manager Templates, AWS CloudFormation.

Scripting: Bash, Powershell, Python.

Automation: Ansible, Azure Resource Manager

Containerisation and Orchestration: Docker.

Networking Configuration.

Database Management: MongoDB, Postgresql, MySQL Server.

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

- Udacity, Remote Nanodegree, Cloud DevOps (June 2022 August 2022)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900).
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer (AZ-204).
- Microsoft Certified: Azure DevOps Engineer (AZ-400) in view
- AWS Certified: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (AWS CLF-CO1)
- Linux Foundation: Certified IT System Admin(LFCS) in view.

WORK HISTORY

Tek Experts, Lagos

Technical Lead. OCTOBER, 2021 - PRESENT

- Provide advanced technical support to corporate customers using Azure
 Web Apps, Azure Function Apps, and Azure DevOps, resolving issues ranging
 from application deployments, failures, and environment configuration.
- 2. Utilize technical documentation, guidance from team members, technical leads, and subject matter experts to research and identify appropriate remediation steps.
- 3. Configure, debug, and fix deployment issues in Azure DevOps CI/CD, GitHub Actions CI/CD, ARM and FTP, supporting developers using open-source stacks such as PHP, NodeJS, Java, JavaScript, and Python.
- 4. Architect and document Azure ARM templates, PowerShell scripts, and Azure Cloud Shell (CLI) commands for automating deployments to Azure PaaS Web Apps, and Function Apps in both Linux and Windows operating systems.
- 5. Facilitate Azure serverless integration and help customers automate business processes using Azure Functions and WebJobs.
- 6. Collaborate with cross-functional teams to ensure timely support delivery within SLAs, develop and implement best practices, and mentor and coach engineers.
- 7. Analyze data to identify trends and opportunities for process improvements, conduct performance evaluations, and provide feedback to team members, ensuring compliance with company policies and procedures.
- 8. Facilitate communication between team members and other departments, engaging customers via remote sessions, email, chat, and phone calls to solve application issues in the production environment.

The I.T Hub, Magboro

Cloud Engineer SEPTEMBER, 2020 - OCTOBER, 2021

- 1. Developed a hybrid cloud delivery model allowing customers to choose the mix of public and private clouds.
- Designed and deployed containerised microservice applications using AWS Cloudformation.
- 3. CI/CD Implementation using AWS CodeDeploy, Jenkins, and GitHub actions.
- Setting up CI/CD pipelines using continuous integration tool Jenkins to automate pipeline scripts for GitHub and GitLab repositories and ansible-playbook execution using AWS CodeDeploy, Jenkins, and GitHub actions.
- Using AWS Budgets to set custom budgets for tracking costs and usage of resources in an AWS account. Setting up alerts by email when actual or forecasted cost and usage exceed the budgeted threshold.
- 6. Hosted several web stack applications (LAMP, LEMP, MERN, MEAN) on Amazon's Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) service to provide secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. I also used Amazon's EC2 Auto Scaling to achieve application availability and scalability in response to traffic patterns. Responsive UI with React.js for individual new features.
- 7. Implemented AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) to securely manage access to AWS services and resources and set up Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) to enhance account security.
- 8. Deploying basic Infrastructure using AWS Cloud Formation, Ansible, and Bash scripting.

Acumen Schools, Magboro

Computer Science teacher and Systems Admin JANUARY, 2018 - SEPTEMBER, 2020

- Ensure the proper functioning, security, and maintenance of computer systems and networks.
- 2. Install, configure, and update hardware and software components, including operating systems, applications, and network devices.
- 3. Monitor system performance, troubleshoot issues, and resolve technical problems to minimize downtime.
- 4. Maintain data backups and implement disaster recovery plans to protect against data loss.
- 5. Conduct regular system audits and implement security measures to detect and prevent unauthorized access or vulnerabilities.
- 6. Collaborate with IT teams and vendors to assess and implement new technologies and system upgrades.
- 7. Worked with kids on game development, coding, and data analysis using Excel and Python.
- 8. Develop and update curriculum materials to ensure students receive relevant and up-to-date instruction in computer science concepts, programming languages, algorithms, and problem-solving skills.
- 9. Deliver engaging lessons and lectures, facilitating discussions and providing

- guidance to students in understanding computer science topics.
- 10. Design and assign projects, assignments, and assessments to evaluate students' understanding and progress.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Received the CEO Global Award for **Stronger Together** in Q4 2022 at Tek Experts for demonstrating exceptional teamwork and collaboration skills within the organization, contributing to the success of several key projects.